[{"question":"<p><strong>A play that stimulates the audience to excessive laughter is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["comedy","farce","climax","tragicomedy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A play that stimulates the audience to excessive laughter is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["comedy","farce","climax","tragicomedy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When literature recreates real events, it is said to be __________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Didactic","Factual","Fictitious","Allegorical"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When literature teaches moral lessons, it is said to be ______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Instructive","Informative","Didactic","Dynamic"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a function of literature.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Inciting","Entertaining","Correcting","Exposing"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>As a medium for exposing and correcting ills in the society literature is ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Allegorical","Satirical","Political","Abusive"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Literature is referred to as a slice of life when it _____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Recounts real event","Entertains its audience","Reveals reality in society","Accuses leaders of insensitiveness"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The time of the events in a literary text is referred to as __ setting<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Special","Spatial","Temporary","Temporal"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What distinguishes drama from other literary genres is that it is meant to be _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Read","Acted","Recited","Viewed"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The writer of a play text is referred to as ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Playwriter","Playwrite","Playright","Playwright"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The major divisions of a novel is called _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chapter","Stanza","Act","Scene"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The perspective from which the story in a novel is narrated is referred to as _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Angle","Focus","Technique","Point of view"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A misuse of a word in place of another one due to similarity in their sounds is known as _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Error","Parallelism","Malapropism","Mistake"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a figure of speech.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Climax","Oxymoron","Antitheses","Mime"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of the following is not a figure of speech.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Climax","Oxymoron","Antitheses","Mime"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_______&nbsp;is an indirect reference to an event, speech or action in the past.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Allusion","Exaggeration","Pun","Innuendo"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Use the poem below to answer question below<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Life is rise and fall<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A tale of comings and goings<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The rhyme scheme of the poem is _______<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Of travails and doings<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>But death ends all<\/strong><\/p>","options":["aabb","aaba","abba","abab"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The central theme of the poem is_____&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hope","Love","Faith","Vanity"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The tone of the poem is that of _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Resignation","Anger","Sorrow","Command"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The type of rhyme in lines 2 and 3 is ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alternate","Internal","Medial","Couplet"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Use the extract below to answer question below<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>William Shakespeare: <em>The Tempest<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker A: The hou&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; s&nbsp; o&nbsp; come<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The very minute bids thee ope thine ear<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Obey, and be attentive. Canst thou remember<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A time before we came unto this cell?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>I do not think thou canst, for then thou wast not<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Out three years old<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker B: Certainly, Sir, I can!<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Who&nbsp; is&nbsp; speaker&nbsp; A?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alonso","Prospero","Antonio","Caliban"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Use the extract below to answer question below<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>William Shakespeare: <em>The Tempest<\/em><\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker A: The hou&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; s&nbsp; o&nbsp; come<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>The very minute bids thee ope thine ear<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Obey, and be attentive. Canst thou remember<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>A time before we came unto this cell?<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>I do not think thou canst, for then thou wast not<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Out three years old<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Speaker B: Certainly, Sir, I can!<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><strong>Who&nbsp; is&nbsp; speaker&nbsp; A?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Alonso","Prospero","Antonio","Caliban"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Speaker B is _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ariel","Caliban","Andrian","Miranda"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The response of speaker B shows that speaker&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>A<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Underrates her memory","Dislikes her behavior","Understands her feelings","Approves of her carriage"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_______<\/strong><strong>is the playwright of <em>Women of Owu<\/em>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Femi Osofisan","Wole Soyinka","Kobina Sekyi","Willam Golding"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major theme in <em>Women of Owu<\/em> is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hatred","Tolerance","Political bigotry","The folly of war"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In <em>Arms and the Man<\/em> Major Saranoff eventually marries_____<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Catherine","Raina","Nicola","Louka"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>______ is the playwright of <em>The Importance of Being Earnest.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Oscar Wide","Oscar Wild","Oscar Wilde","Oscar Wade"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>_________<\/strong><strong>misplaced Jack Worthing in a leader handbag.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cecily","Gwendolen","Mrs. Prism","Lady Bracknell"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>One of these characters in <em>The Importance of Being Earnest<\/em> is a clergy.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Algemon","Cardew","Brackell","Chasuble"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Who is the author of <em>Lord of the Flies<\/em>?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Williams Shakespeare","Lord Baron","Williams Golding","Earnest Hemmingway"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A predominant theme in <em>Lord of the Flies<\/em> is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The innateness of evil","Religious fanaticism","Necessity for social order","The uselessness of adult"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which song is meant to lull a baby to sleep?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ballad","Lullaby","Dirge","Ode"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The last six lines of a patrachan sonnet is called ________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Septet","Quatrain","Sextet","Octave"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A quatrain contains __ lines.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Five","Three","Four","Six"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>__&nbsp; is a moment of relief in a tragic play brought about through a comic scene.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong><br \/>&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tragic relief","Comic relief","Suspense","Comedy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>is a device used to bring past event into focus to clarify present events in literature.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Prologue","Exposition","Foreshadowing","Flashback"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A reference to a work of art, person or place whether directly or indirectly is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["allusion","contrast","assonance","allegory"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Literature, a Dramatis Personae refers to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the name of the author","the list of characters in a play","the name of the central character in a play","the voice of the characters in a play"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a writer refers to past events to throw more light on current ones, he is employing<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a retrospection","flashback","historical drama","dramatic shift"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a type of poem?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sonnet","Elegy","Pantomime","Ode"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major narrative technique a novel shares with drama is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["scenes","dialogue","soliloquy","sarcasm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>A reference to a work of art, person or place whether directly or indirectly is called<\/strong><\/p>","options":["allusion","contrast","assonance","allegory"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>In Literature, a Dramatis Personae refers to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["the name of the author","the list of characters in a play","the name of the central character in a play","the voice of the characters in a play"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a writer refers to past events to throw more light on current ones, he is employing<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a retrospection","flashback","historical drama","dramatic shift"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a type of poem?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Sonnet","Elegy","Pantomime","Ode"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>One major narrative technique a novel shares with drama is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["scenes","dialogue","soliloquy","sarcasm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A blank verse<\/p>","options":["is a nonsensical verse","consists of unrhymed five stress lines","is a verse used by the nobility","consists of rhyme in the second and fourth line"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>\"See! how she leans her cheek upon her hand; O! that! wore a glove upon that hand <\/em><\/p>\n<p><em>That I might touch that cheek.\"<\/em><\/p>\n<p>The predominant figure of speech in these lines in&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["conceit","apostrophe","caricature","simile"],"answerIndex":"0","examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The technique used in bringing the plot of a play to an abrupt end is called<\/p>","options":["denouement","climax","endnote","dues ex machina"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>\"Stream of consciousness\" is the name for&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["an Italian rhyme scheme brought into vogue in the sixteenth century","a stage device in which an actor addresses the audience directly","a cultural phenomenon of the eighteenth century"],"answerIndex":"0","examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A blank verse<\/p>","options":["is a nonsensical verse","consists of unrhymed five stress lines","is a verse used by the nobility","consists of rhyme in the second and fourth line"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p><em>\"See! how she leans her cheek upon her hand; O! that! wore a glove upon that hand <\/em><\/p>\n<p><em>That I might touch that cheek.\"<\/em><\/p>\n<p>The predominant figure of speech in these lines in&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["conceit","apostrophe","caricature","simile"],"answerIndex":"0","examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The technique used in bringing the plot of a play to an abrupt end is called<\/p>","options":["denouement","climax","endnote","dues ex machina"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on General Literary Principles and Appreciation<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>\"Stream of consciousness\" is the name for&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["an Italian rhyme scheme brought into vogue in the sixteenth century","a stage device in which an actor addresses the audience directly","a cultural phenomenon of the eighteenth century"],"answerIndex":"0","examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Which of the following was not written by Chinua Achebe?<\/p>","options":["Girls at war","Anthills of the Salvador","No longer at Ease","Arrow of God"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>\"Even now that the typhoon of your tongue is blowing away the roof of my refuge, leaving me with showers of your kindness\"<\/p>\n<p>The most prominent figure of speech in the above is<\/p>","options":["hyperbole","contrast","metonymy","metaphor"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Rhyme and rhythm are elements of<\/p>","options":["cultural poetry","musical poetry","colonial poetry","pastoral"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A mental picture created with words is referred to as&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["illusion","image","symbol","fiction"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>The representation of a thing with something closely associated with it is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["epigram","metonymy","synecdoche","symbolism"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Parallelism involves similarity in&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["structure","syntax","sound","lines"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>An iambic pentameter poem without a rhyme scheme is a&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["free verse","blind verse","blank verse","iambus"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a kind of imagery?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["offertory imagery","tactile imagery","visual imagery","kinesthetic imagery"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a figurative expression in <em><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">An African Thunderstorm<\/span><\/em> by Rubadirt?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["pregnant clouds","plaque of locusts","tattered flags","dangling breasts"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The line <em>\"Your mouth, O katty is a museum with many monuments\"<\/em> is both<\/p>","options":["metaphor and hyperbolic","a synecdoche and a metonymy","metaphoric and epigrammatic","a metaphor and an allusion"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A premiere is&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["a soap opera","the first play by a playwright","a play with social criticism in it","the first performance of a play"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A long narrative in which the fate of a community is dependent on the life and activities of the hero is<\/p>","options":["A tragedy","A legend","An epic","A historical narrative"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>Point of view in Literature is related to<\/p>","options":["the narrator","the author","the setting","the hero"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary concepts<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>Setting refers to both<\/p>","options":["time and place","place and space","place and mood","place and culture"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary principles<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>The main purpose of a satire is to<\/p>\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["heighten the personality of the main character in a story","attack the government","incite the reader to rebellion","ridicule or treat a subject or idea with contempt"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary principles<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>A prologue usually occurs at the&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["middle of a poem","end of a novel","beginning of a play","none of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Based on general literary principles<\/strong><\/p>\n<p>In a literary work, the character whom the hero struggles against is called his<\/p>","options":["alter ego","opposite","mentor","antagonist"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Out, Out, thou strumpet fortune! All ye gods,&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>In general synod, take away her power,<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Break all the spokes and fellies from her wheel<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>And bowl the round knave down the hill of heaven<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>As low as to the friends<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p>In the above lines, the persona is<\/p>","options":["enchanted with fortune","praying to the gods for good fortune","intensely angry with fortune","none of the above"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><em><strong>Out, Out, thou strumpet fortune! All ye gods,&nbsp;<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>In general synod, take away her power,<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>Break all the spokes and fellies from her wheel<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>And bowl the round knave down the hill of heaven<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em><strong>As low as to the friends<\/strong><\/em><\/p>\n<p><em>The device adopted in talking of fortune is<\/em><\/p>","options":["pomposity","analogy","axiom","personification"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"}]